

Alberto Sanchez

GAME DEVELOPER in Barcelona, Spain

CONTACT



(+34) 678 264 135



alberto93.dev@gmail.com



www.vosthek.com

SKILLS

Engines: Unity, Unreal, Custom Languages: C/C++, C#, Python,

HLSL/GLSL, MaxScript

Tools: Visual*, Git, SVN, 3DSMax, Maya, Adobe, RenderDoc, Nvidia

Nsight

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native Catalan: Native English: Fluent

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science

Universitat Pompeu Fabra 2011-2016

Masters in Videogame Creation

Universitat Pompeu Fabra 2017-2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Co-founder & Technical Director

Baby Robot Games

[2019 - 2024]

- Co-founder of Baby Robot Games, videogame studio based in Spain, developed <u>Ereban: Shadow Legacy</u> in collaboration with <u>Raw Fury</u> publishing.
- Technical direction and management of the technical team.
- Lead graphics programming (Shaders, Rendering pipeline)
- · Lead, gameplay and tools programming.
- Performance & optimizations.

Associate Professor

Universitat Oberta de Catalunya

[2021 - Now]

• Tutor for undergraduate final degree videogame projects.

Associate Professor

Universitat La Salle

[2018 - 2021]

- Tools programming lecturer for Master's degree.
- Unity tools, 3DSMax & Custom Engine tools (C#, C++, Maxscript, Python).
- Definition of an asset integration pipeline using a custom engine.

Software Engineer / Technical Artist

Mobile Media Content

[2016 - 2019]

- Development of Unity3D AR/VR and desktop applications.
- Technical artist, creation of a series of tooling pipelines for 3DSMax, Unity3D and AutoCAD.
- Research and development of computer graphics algorithms to automate and improve 3D virtual environments.

Software Engineer

Avanade

[2015 - 2016]

- Dynamics AXS programmer at Avanade.
- Enterprise resource planning at greenfield project for Media Markt.

ABOUT ME

Passionate about videogames since childhood, specially caught by the technology behind them.

I truly enjoy graphics and engine programming, where I always try to understand the low level first to better understand the high level.

I had the opportunity to co-found Baby Robot Games, where during five years I was in charge of the technical direction of the company, developing Ereban: Shadow Legacy.

I love to share knowledge of game development, making another of my passions to teach. I've given lectures at many different institutions, and I am a currently teaching at UOC University.

PROJECTS

Ereban: Shadow Legacy

Baby Robot Games (2019 - 2024)
Tags: C#, Unity, HDRP, HLSL, VFXGraph

Ereban: Shadow Legacy is a fast-paced stealth platformer game where you become Ayana, the last descendant of a forgotten race. Harness mystical shadow powers, high-tech gadgets and avoid or kill to uncover the truth about your past and the key to saving a dying, morally grey universe.

Atlas' Fate: Between Light & Darkness

Baby Robot Games (2018)

Tags: C++, Directx, HLSL, Custom Engine

Atlas' Fate: Between Light & Darkness is a 3rd person stealth game where you take control of a stealth expert with the ability to merge with the shadows. This power allows him to move without being seen, move through walls, cushion falls or pass through obstacles.

SIDE PROJECTS

Unknot Engine

Self (2022)

Tags: Directx, C++, HLSL,

Custom engine developed from scratch, using DirectX. The aim of the engine is to create a basic engine template with its series of own tools to keep learning and improving the bases of graphics and engine programming.

Assault Birds

Self (2015)

Tags: Directx, C++, HLSL,

Videogame developed in C ++ from scratch using OpenGL. The aim of the project is to experiment with graphic programming, specially with shaders, creating reflections for water, shadows, water distortions and post-processing effects, among others.

COD-ModSource

Self (2008)

Tags: C, QuakeScript

Series of Call of Duty 2 mods created in collaboration with the modder (Mitch Hubers). The mod reached top five popularity in the mod scene community.